[Music]
California was the first state to
legalize medical marijuana when Labs
started reporting that they were finding
high levels of pesticide residues the LA
City Government covertly Acquired and
then tested three samples from
dispensaries and found that two of the
three samples did have exceedingly High
pesticide levels up to a thousand times
the legal
limit yeah but how much ends up inside
the consumer only about 10% or so of
pesticides in tobacco makes it through a
filtered
cigarette which was found to be
comparable to using cannabis in a water
pipe with filters attached but use a
regular bong about half the pesticides
end up in your lungs and a glass pipe is
even
worse because most users don't attach a
carbon filter to their bongs with 7 and
12 grams of activated charcoal in
general the portion of pesticide
recovery from Cannabis would be
alarmingly high and is a serious concern
although we don't know precisely how
damaging these chemicals are the fact
that they're present in smoke at such
high levels should be
concerning considering these results
high pesticide exposure through cannabis
smoking is a significant possibility
which may lead to further Health
complications in cannabis consumers
especially if we're talking about
medical marijuana sick vulnerable people
but potentially making things
worse the potential of pesticide and
chemical residue exposure to cannabis
users is substantial and may pose a
significant toxicological threat in the
absence of adequate regulatory
Frameworks okay so what are states doing
about it Colorado recently suffered some
high-profile recalls of marijuana
batches contaminated with harmful
pesticides that made into some of the
Edibles evidently Growers times find
themselves overwhelmed by pest issues
and resort to nuclear tactics trying
anything to protect their
crop this has created a public health
threat with intensified toxicity and
concentrated products of particular
concern pesticide levels were found to
be approximately 10 times higher in
concentrated cannabis products like the
oils and waxes sometimes used in Edibles
or dabbed as
concentrates a study of pesticide use on
cannabis crops in or oron found a
similar problem a survey of samples off
store shelves in Washington state found
five out of six contaminated including
with potentially neurotoxic and
carcinogenic agents many samples
harbored multiple contaminants attaining
levels basically off the charts
including 24 distinct pesticide agents
insecticides fungicides none of which
are approved for use in cannabis but
it's not their fault the EPA hasn't
approved any because it's still a
federally illegal crop in fact testing
labs in California have become hesitant
to publicize their service or or List
agents for which they could test as they
suspect that such information might be
used as like an instruction manual by
unscrupulous Growers to seek out even
more toxic
agents okay so just regulate it they've
tried but guess what was the biggest
barrier they came up against surprise
surprise the Cannabis industry the
multi-billion doll cannabis industry
like the tobacco industry before the
Cannabis industry is attempting to
weaken pesticide
regulations reportedly the Colorado
Department of Agriculture initially
hoped to limit permissible pesticides to
the most
non-toxic but this proposal was quashed
by industry push back just like the
tobacco industry was able to do big
tobacco has provided a detailed road map
for King cannabis deny addiction
potential downplay any adverse health
effects create as large a market as
quickly as possible and protect that
market through lobbying and campaign
contributions bolstered by enormous
profits the tobacco industry was able to
get itself Exempted from every major
piece of consumer protection legislation
so that should be a cautionary tale for
us now given that public health
Advocates have definitively fewer
billions to work
with big tobacco may not just be
providing the road map but waiting in
the wings to own the
road as a result of lawsuits against the
tobacco industry more than 80 million
pages of internal company documents
became available and what they reveal is
that since at least 1970 despite fervent
denials major multinational tobacco
companies like Philip Morris have been
scheming willing and prepared to enter
the legalized marijuana Market to become
big
blunt because the tobacco industry's
demonstrated ability and willingness to
modify its products to increase
addictiveness obfuscate information
deceive the public and Target vulnerable
groups to increased demand the industry
has the power to dramatically change the
game
[Music]
I